welcome to another installment of spring
欢迎来到 Spring 的另一期
tips in this week's installment we're
在本周分期付款中的提示
going to look at spring cloud gateway
去看一下Spring Cloud Gateway
spring cloud gateway is a new technology
Spring Cloud Gateway是一项新技术
that's designed to provide a lot of the
旨在提供很多
same gateway style functionality that
相同的网关样式功能
you may be familiar with if you've ever
您可能曾经熟悉过
used Netflix Zul in this installment
在本期中使用Netflix Zul
we're gonna look at some of the features
我们将看一些功能
at Spring cloud Gateway provides out of
在Spring Cloud Gateway提供的
the box some of the some of which you
盒子里的一些你
may not find in in for example Netflix
可能无法在Netflix中找到
is a Azul
是蔚蓝
now the question may arise of course why
现在可能会出现问题，为什么
did we create a spring flood gateway if
我们是否创建了 Spring 洪水门户，如果
we already had a Netflix zoom there's a
我们已经有了Netflix变焦
number of reasons first of all Netflix
首先是Netflix的原因数量
Zul itself has not really seen a lot of
祖尔（Zul）本身并没有真正看到很多
sort of evolution it hasn't evolved
尚未进化的某种进化
hasn't advanced very much in recent
最近没有进步很多
recent time so we're not sure where the
最近一次，所以我们不确定
project is headed we know that Netflix
该项目的进行我们知道Netflix
is old too isn't here yet and that was a
还老了还不在这里，那是一个
release that was supposed to be more in
释放本来应该更多
line with what we were hoping to have
与我们希望拥有的一致
including a support for an integration
包括对整合的支持
with reactive technologies like for
与诸如
example project reactor and as a result
示例反应堆，结果
it doesn't have some of the features
它没有某些功能
that work you know a lot of people have
你知道很多人的工作
been clamoring for including support for
一直在呼吁包括支持
proxying other kinds of protocols like
代理其他类型的协议，例如
WebSockets for example as well as a sort
WebSockets以及一种
of more flexible component model so a
更灵活的组件模型
lot of these things that we want in in a
我们想要的很多这些东西
sort of integration in the solution we
解决方案中的某种整合
don't have they're all so and very you
没有他们都是如此，非常你
know very understandably also you'll
非常了解你也会
find that Netflix Zul doesn't open
发现Netflix Zul无法打开
source a lot of the really useful stuff
采购很多真正有用的东西
things like rate limiters right that
诸如限速器之类的东西
stuff that is proprietary to Netflix
Netflix专有的内容
it's the way they do it themselves it
这是他们自己做的方式
may of course and it may not be the best
可能当然，也可能不是最好的
solution for everybody and so naturally
所有人的解决方案，自然而然
completely understandably that hasn't
完全可以理解的是
been open sourced until we you know we
一直开源，直到我们知道
as a community of and forced to fend for
作为一个社区并被迫捍卫
ourselves they're not a big deal but
我们自己，这没什么大不了，但
that's one of those things you can get
那就是你可以得到的那些东西之一
out of box in spring cloud gateway so
在 Spring Cloud 网关中开箱即用
let's take a look at that we're going to
让我们来看看我们要
take a look at that today but before we
看看今天，但在我们之前
build an edge service let's just build a
建立边缘服务，让我们建立一个
downstream service to talk to and in
与之对话的下游服务
order to talk to in order to discover it
为了交谈以发现它
and find it we're gonna stand up a
找到它，我们将站起来
service registry so we'll do that first
服务注册表，因此我们将首先这样做
well create a eureka service here just
在这里创建一个尤里卡服务
as normal right and hit generate and
像往常一样右击并产生
we'll go to our IDE here whatever
我们将在这里转到我们的IDE
there is this I'm gonna open this up in
我要在这里打开它
our ID and it will make some changes to
我们的ID，它将对
a to make it available so that other
一个使其可用，以便其他
micro services including the service
微服务，包括服务
that were going to build and our edge
那将要建立的和我们的优势
service our gateway can find two things
服务我们的网关可以找到两件事
right so first things first we're going
对，所以首先要做的是
to make this an application a spring
使这个应用成为 Spring
mood of spring boot application that
spring boot 应用的心情
runs on port 87-61 I'm going to say that
在端口87-61上运行我要说的是
well Eureka to register itself with
尤里卡（Eureka）可以向自己注册
itself and devil to say that as false
自己和魔鬼说那是假的
and what I want to find when I fetch the
以及我在获取时要查找的内容
registry no need we are the registry so
注册表不需要我们是注册表所以
we'll do both of those or rather well
我们会做到这两者或做得更好
not do those I'm going to say that name
不做那些我要说的名字
will you Rica server now that that
Rica服务器现在可以吗
should be it right we have here on the
应该是正确的，我们在这里
classpath spring card starter eureka
classpathSpring 卡启动器尤里卡
server so believe that as is and start
服务器，因此请相信并开始
that up that'll be on port 87-61 now
现在将在端口87-61上
once that's done we can now build a a
一旦完成，我们现在可以建立一个
customer service something to talk to
客服谈谈
now this service is going to use the new
现在，该服务将使用新的
latest and greatest service reactive bit
最新和最大的服务响应位
so 2.0 and 6 for spring boot we use
所以我们用2.0和6来做 spring boot
reactive web reactive MongoDB we use
我们使用的反应式Web反应式MongoDB
Lombok naturally I wouldn't need the
lombok 自然，我不需要
Eureka's server support we do want you
我们希望您能获得尤里卡的服务器支持
Iike discovery so we'll bring that in
Iike发现，所以我们将其引入
and otherwise I think that's it so we
否则我认为就是这样
might you know actuator that's probably
您可能知道执行器可能
a good idea right so we've got those
一个好主意，所以我们有那些
bits let's hit generate and open this up
让我们点击生成并打开它
customer service alright so first things
客户服务还好，所以第一件事
first we're gonna give this a name
首先，我们要给它起个名字
spring application name equals customer
Spring 申请名称等于客户
- service and then customer service
-服务，然后是客户服务
itself is going to participate in
本身要参加
service registration and discover right
服务注册和发现权
now as of as of springtime Finchley
现在截至 Spring Finchley
which is what we're using on the
这就是我们在
classpath we no longer need the at nit
我们不再需要classpath
will discovery client annotation right
将发现客户端注释正确
you've probably become accustomed to
你可能已经习惯了
doing that
那样做
that's not need anymore but that is in
那不再需要了
place right so when we start this
放置正确，所以当我们开始这个
application up it'll register itself
应用程序将注册自己
with the service registry so again this
与服务注册表，所以再次
is gonna be an application manage what
将成为一个应用程序管理什么
entities of type of customer just a
客户类型的实体只是一个
strawman example here strong and domain
稻草人的例子在这里强而有力
so private string ID private string name
因此，私有字符串ID私有字符串名称
let's say an ID
假设一个ID
and document there we are there's our
并记录那里，我们在那里
entity now we need a at data at arcs
现在我们需要一个at数据
constructor at nowhere it's constructed
构造函数在没有构造的地方
here all from Lombok they just they
这里所有来自 lombok 的人
synthesize a constructors Gator setters
合成构造函数Gator setter
two string methods all that kind of
两种字符串方法
stuff and of course we need something
的东西，当然我们需要一些东西
with which to manipulate instances of
用它来操纵
this type so create a repository extends
这种类型，因此创建存储库扩展
reactive Mongo repository manage the
反应性Mongo存储库管理
entities of typed customer whose primary
主要客户的类型客户的实体
keys of type long and then we'll save
类型为long的键，然后我们将保存
from data in the database so it'll be an
来自数据库中的数据，因此它将是
application runner in it and we're going
应用程序运行器，我们要
to inject the customer repository here
在这里注入客户资料库
and we'll say return
我们会说回报
CR start wrote a return args and we're
CR开始写了一个返回参数，我们
gonna say CR delete all then C then
要说CR删除所有然后C然后
we'll say flux just a b c map to a you
我们会说助焊剂只是abc映射到您
know a new customer object here so
在这里认识一个新的客户对象
there's this no for the ID l for the
的ID为l
name and then map that to a record that
命名，然后将其映射到记录
we saved in the database like so alright
我们像这样保存在数据库中
and then I'm gonna say CR to find all
然后我要说CR找到所有
and it will subscribe so system out
它将订阅系统
print line alright good so there we are
打印行还不错，所以我们到了
there's our date in the database now we
现在数据库中有我们的日期
want to have an endpoint by which to
想要有一个端点来
access this stuff so we'll take
访问这些东西，我们将采取
advantage of the spring one flex the
Spring 一弯曲的优点
reactive web runtime instead of a Spring
反应式Web运行时而不是Spring
Framework 5 so we'll say router
框架5，所以我们说路由器
functions router function routes routes
功能路由器功能路由路由
I turn router of functions dot route
打开功能点路由器
requests predicates get and first
请求predicate先获取
endpoint of course is customers right so
当然终点是客户，所以
I wanna say given a request then return
我想说一个请求然后返回
a response so server response dot ok dot
响应，以便服务器响应点ok点
body we're going to inject the customer
身体，我们要注入客户
repository here to do our work so CR CR
储存库在这里做我们的工作，所以CR CR
to find all
找到所有
customer dot class there's that and we
客户点类就是这样，我们
have some other routes as well let's
还有其他路线，让我们
clean things up simplify things just a
整理东西简化事情
wee bit here so get rid of all that good
有点在这里，所以摆脱所有的好处
and what else do we want we want to get
还有我们想要得到什么
customers ID are ok dot body CR that
客户ID可以的点体CR
find my ID and I will say customer net
找到我的身份证，我会说客户网
class there we are good and we want one
上课，我们很好，我们想要一个
more endpoint and this one is going to
更多端点，这将是
it's going to be something that we can
这将是我们可以做的
use to introduce a delay so we just call
用于引入延迟，因此我们只调用
it just that we'll call it delay and
只是我们称之为延迟而已
we're going to say given a request just
我们要说的只是一个请求
hello world
你好，世界
all right given a request when you delay
延迟时可以提出要求
the elements by 10 seconds right there
元素就在那里10秒
we are and we're going to return this
我们是，我们将返回这个
whole thing this whole delayed publisher
整个事情都推迟了
as a response so ok dot body ok pass
作为回应，所以点体还可以
that back like so there we are there's
像这样回来我们在那里
our endpoints with see if that all works
我们的端点，看看是否一切正常
all right
好吧
there we are okay
那里我们还好
not right we can go to the console here
不对，我们可以在这里进入控制台
curl HTP localhost:8080 for such
卷曲HTP localhost ：8080这样
customers seems to be okay let's try a
客户似乎还可以，让我们尝试
particular record here I'll take this
特别的记录在这里
there's a single record let's prove that
有一个记录让我们证明
the delay in point is working one two
点的延迟是一两个
three four five six seven eight nine ten
三四五六七七八九十
is there we are all right
有没有我们可以
so there's a record so that's all
所以有一张唱片就这样
working all of our endpoints are working
所有的端点都在工作
we'll look at why we need this delayed
我们将看看为什么我们需要延迟
response a little bit later okay but
稍等一下就可以了
we've got now three different end points
现在我们有了三个不同的终点
we can use that as our is our you know
我们可以使用它，因为我们就是我们知道的
our harness if you will our feedback
如果您愿意我们的反馈意见
mechanism so now let's go build a edge
机制，现在让我们建立一个优势
source so I'm gonna go back to start to
源，所以我要回去开始
spring that IO we're gonna use the
Spring ，我们将使用
latest in greatest it spring booped
最新的最大 Spring
it's going to use the actuator or use
将要使用执行器或使用
the the gateway support it used the
它使用的网关支持
reactive web support as well of course
反应式网络支持
so reactive web I want to use what else
所以反应性的网站，我想用别的
do we need huh we need the security
我们需要吗我们需要安全
support so let's see here
支持，让我们在这里看看
security you need Redis support and I
安全，需要Redis支持，我
think that'll do I think that's enough
认为那会做我认为就足够了
let me check let me think about this
让我检查一下让我考虑一下
here we've got the reactive web support
在这里，我们有反应性的网络支持
we have security we want the historic
我们有安全，我们想要历史
support the circuit breaker and red is
支持断路器，红色为
web looks alright
网络看起来还不错
Oh Eureka naturally we need that of
哦，尤里卡（Eureka）当然需要
course so here's this as well very good
当然，这也是很好
I'm going to call this the edge service
我将其称为边缘服务
and this will of course interact with
这当然会与
our downstream customer service with the
我们的下游客户服务
via the service registry the very same
通过服务注册表完全一样
one that we just stood up so edge
我们刚站起来的那一副
service we are
我们服务
all right so we have a new application
好的，所以我们有一个新的应用程序
let's see edge service application our
让我们看看边缘服务应用程序
application is going to be a spring
申请将是 Spring
cloud Gateway project and if you've used
cloud Gateway项目，如果您曾经使用过
Netflix Zul with spring cloud then you
带有 Spring Cloud 的Netflix Zul，然后您
know that one of the nice things you can
知道你可以做的一件好事
do is say enable Zul server and or
就是说启用Zul服务器，或者
unable dual proxy and it'll
无法双重代理，它将
automatically set up route for you on
自动为您设置路线
the edge service that mapped to the
映射到
routes in the service registry so we can
路由在服务注册表中，因此我们可以
get the similar effect that's first of
得到与第一个相似的效果
all participate in service registration
都参加服务注册
and discovery by saying you know by
通过说你知道而发现
giving it a name and we also want to
给它起个名字，我们也想
differentiate our port otherwise we'll
区分我们的港口，否则我们会
have a port collision and we can get the
发生端口冲突，我们可以得到
same effect just by doing route and then
只是通过做路线，然后
we can do a discovery client route
我们可以做发现客户路线
definition locator so DS you know
定义定位器，因此您知道DS
discovery routes and of course in order
发现路线，当然是有序的
for us to configure this we need a
为我们进行配置，我们需要一个
discovery client I say new discovery
发现客户，我说新发现
client route definition locator all
客户端路由定义定位器全部
right let's see what we get when you run
好的，让我们看看您跑步时会得到什么
this application
这个应用程序
all right now already I can see a
现在已经可以看到
problem I can see a problem already
问题我已经看到一个问题
because we don't have security first of
因为我们首先没有安全性
all well so no did that instance worked
很好，所以那个实例没有用
so 87-61 our service registry isn't
所以我们的服务注册表不是87-61
running right now why not
现在跑步为什么不
okay
好的
I neglected to start it before we got
我忽略了开始之前
into it so there it is now it's happy
进入它，所以现在很快乐
the customer service is happy where we
客户服务令我们满意
start this and it'll still fail for
启动它，它仍然会失败
reasons I just mentioned which is that
我刚才提到的原因是
we forgot to disable security for the
我们忘记了为
moment so let's go back and remove
片刻，让我们回去删除
security from our build just for the
我们提供的安全性仅用于
moment we'll bring it back in a minute
一会儿我们会把它拿回来
and where we start all right run
我们从哪里开始一切正常
very good so if we go here localhost
很好，所以如果我们去 localhost
curl
卷曲
they should be localhost:8080 one
他们应该是localhost：8080一
customer - service for such customers
客户-为此类客户提供服务
Ecuador look at that we have the the
厄瓜多尔看看我们有
customers being proxied from the
客户被代理
downstream service and of course that's
下游服务，那当然是
load balancing away so that's the
负载平衡了，所以
equivalent to the one-liner annotation
相当于单线注释
in the zoo world but we can do a lot
在动物园里，但是我们可以做很多事情
more right there's actually a number of
更正确的是实际上有许多
different ways to do more there's
做更多事情的不同方法
actually a property-based mechanism as
实际上是一种基于财产的机制
well I happen to prefer the Java
好吧，我碰巧更喜欢Java
configuration DSL so I want to use that
配置DSL，所以我想使用
and the way that works is you create a
而有效的方法是您创建一个
route locator object so Gateway routes
路由定位器对象，因此网关路由
and you use the route dot locator dot
然后使用路线点定位器点
DSL and that looks like this so routes
DSL，看起来像这样，所以路由
that locator dot build and here is where
定位点的建立，这是在哪里
we create our different routes so that's
我们创建了不同的路线，因此
create a very simple route just a basic
创建一个非常简单的路线，只是一个基本的
proxy first okay and this is going to be
代理首先好，这将是
a endpoint that we're just gonna call
我们将要呼叫的端点
start it's gonna be a route called start
开始，这将是一条称为开始的路线
that's going to match a certain
这将匹配某个
predicate and there's a number of things
predicate，有很多事情
you can use here for predicates you
您可以在这里使用predicate
could say path right I want you know
可以说正确的道路，我想让你知道
whenever somebody makes a request to the
每当有人向
edge service itself I want that to be to
边缘服务本身，我希望成为
match a path you know force that start
匹配您知道开始的路径
and and so on I could also do much more
等等，我还可以做更多
interesting things I could do host you
我可以做的有趣的事情来接待你
know route request predicate stat host
知道路由请求predicate统计主机
equals a you know food calm and chain
等于您知道食物平静和连锁
them together alright so it has to equal
他们在一起很好所以必须平等
food calm you know so wild start free to
食物平静，你知道如此疯狂地开始自由
come and then go to the four slash but
来然后去到四个斜杠
in our case since I don't have any hosts
就我们而言，因为我没有任何主机
or V host set for my local machine will
或为我的本地计算机设置的V主机
just do that okay so there's our request
这样做就可以了，所以有我们的要求
predicate and then we would need to make
predicate，然后我们需要
a request to an actual endpoint so let's
对实际端点的请求，让我们
just for now proxy the happiest place on
就目前而言，代理最幸福的地方
earth starts out spring at i/o four
地球在I / O 4开始 Spring
slash eighty alright so that's a basic
斜线八十好吧，这是一个基本的
proxy we're not you know when somebody
代理我们不是你知道什么时候有人
goes to localhost 8080 one for such
去 localhost 8080这样的
start they're gonna get the contents of
开始，他们将得到的内容
this as though it was rendered on this
好像是在此渲染
machine so let's try that
机器，所以让我们尝试一下
localhost:8080 one forward slash start
localhost ：8080一个正斜杠开始
there we are
我们在那里
there's our you know some of the style
我们知道一些风格
sheets and other assets that are linked
工作表和其他链接的资产
relative to the server there aren't
相对于服务器没有
working but that is indeed the output
工作，但这确实是输出
from the actual web service right so
从实际的Web服务开始
we've got all that for you know for free
我们为您免费提供了所有这些
and it's very very quick you can see the
而且很快就可以看到
the proxy doesn't slack here at all
代理完全没有懈怠
notice that I had to specify the port
注意，我必须指定端口
that's one thing that made trip you up
那是让你绊倒的一件事
remember to specify the port otherwise
记得要指定端口
it will assume port 8080 which is of
它将使用端口8080
course what or 8081 in this case because
在这种情况下当然是8081
that's the port that we're using that's
这就是我们正在使用的端口
not what you want all right so it's a
不是您想要的所有东西，所以这是一个
basic proxy you can do other kinds of
基本代理，你可以做其他种类的
things here you may remember that Zul
这里的事情你可能还记得祖尔
can be made load balancing a waiter's so
可以使服务员的负载达到平衡
load balanced proxy right so here we're
负载均衡代理正确，所以在这里
going to say that we want to get the
会说我们想得到
customers right the DC I guess we could
客户正确的DC我想我们可以
say or that will be there you go the
说或那将在那里你去
predicate will be path L II and the URI
predicate将是路径L II和URI
it's going to be LD : customer - service
这将是LD：客户-服务
forward slash customer so we're actually
正斜杠客户，所以我们实际上是
now taking advantage of a eureka aware
现在利用尤里卡意识
URI alright this is a gonna talk to the
URI好吧，这将与
service registry it's gonna give us back
服务注册表，它将给我们回馈
the results etc it's gonna do what we
结果等它将做我们所要做的
would have expected but without having
本来期望但没有
to spend very much time at all so here
花很多时间在这里
we are we said lb there's the customers
我们是说，有客户
you know they what happened there is
你知道他们那里发生了什么
that the client went to the users spring
客户去了用户 Spring
cloud discover client abstraction went
云发现客户端抽象去了
to the service registry got all the
到服务注册表得到了所有
service instances back then pass out to
服务实例返回，然后传递给
something like ribbon ribbon did clients
像缎带一样的东西做客户
had load balancing and we picked an
有负载平衡，我们选择了一个
instance and routed the request
实例并路由请求
ultimately set for total instance all of
最终将全部实例设置为
that happened in the blink of an eye so
眨眼间就发生了
that's a very convenient okay so that's
这很方便，所以
a very simple proxy that's that works
一个非常简单的代理服务器就可以了
but we can do more interesting things as
但是我们可以做更多有趣的事情
well we could for example introduce
好吧，我们可以例如介绍
custom filters right so let's do that
自定义过滤器，这样就可以了
here a custom filter one right and we're
这里是一个自定义过滤器，我们
gonna say route C f1
要说路线C f1
and predicates will be path equals 2 CF
predicate的路径等于2 CF
1 and the URI will be load balanced
1，并且URI将实现负载均衡
customer - service for such customers
客户-为此类客户提供服务
but before we do that we need to filter
但是在我们这样做之前，我们需要过滤
all right those number ways you can
好吧，那些数字方式
specify the filter you can spin specify
指定您可以旋转指定的过滤器
it wanted it one at a time or provide
它一次想要一个或提供
them all in particular order I'm gonna
他们都按照特定的顺序
do this one and our filter will just be
做到这一点，我们的过滤器将是
very simple one we're gonna create a
非常简单的一个，我们要创建一个
custom one by default so we're gonna say
默认情况下自定义一个，所以我们要说
exchange chain equals and our job is
交换链等于我们的工作是
then to to respond so we're gonna say a
然后回应，所以我们要说一个
filter sorry rest a chain filter
过滤器对不起休息链过滤器
exchange in this case we're just gonna
在这种情况下交换，我们只是
you know it's just like the server the
你知道这就像服务器
filter API kind of we're going to
过滤器API，我们将要
actually call recursively the other
实际递归调用另一个
filters in the chain and then we're
过滤链，然后我们
going to process the response so then
要处理响应，然后
I'm going to say mono dot from runnable
我要说的是可运行的单点
and we're going to say I'm going to
我们要说我要
provide a runnable here that gets
提供一个可运行的地方
processed that gets run after the
处理后运行
processing of the of all the downstream
所有下游的处理
chained filters right so we're gonna do
链式过滤器正确，所以我们要做
something like this we're gonna say
这样的话我们要说
exchange dot what what I'm gonna say get
交换点我要说些什么
response exchange not get response I'm
回应交流未得到回应
gonna store that in a variable there so
要将其存储在变量中
server HTTP response good
服务器HTTP响应良好
and I'll say HTTP response dot status
我会说HTTP响应点状态
code and let's just fix them I don't
代码，让我们修复它们，我不
care it conflict okay there's that it
关心它冲突好吧，有它
should be response dot heteros dot
应为响应点，异质点
content type media type PDF all right so
内容类型媒体类型PDF可以，所以
that's a very simple filter filter so
这是一个非常简单的过滤器过滤器，所以
now when somebody goes to four to five
现在有人去四点到五点
CF one they should see that it doesn't
CF他们应该看到它没有
return that status or that content type
返回该状态或内容类型
that we would have gotten from the
那本来可以从
actual service and the actual service
实际服务和实际服务
you may remember of course we can get to
您可能还记得我们当然可以
by going to LV so let's compare here so
去LV，让我们在这里比较一下
LV vs. CF one if we go here to LV - V
LV vs. CF如果我们到这里去LV-V
for verbose to see the details there
详细查看那里的详细信息
it's H to be 200 and content type is
H为200，内容类型为
equal to advocate in JSON
等于在JSON中倡导
that's the original web service
那是原始的网络服务
basically and here we're going to use CF
基本上，这里我们将使用CF
one
一
you can see that we get 4/9 conflict and
您可以看到我们遇到了4/9冲突，
of course the content type is PDF which
当然，内容类型是PDF
in this case you know there's no there's
在这种情况下，你知道那里没有
no rhyme or reason to this obviously
显然没有韵律或理由
that's nonsense this is not what the
那是胡说八道这不是什么
actual service returned and there's no
实际服务返回了，没有了
reason to send it back in this case I'm
在这种情况下将其寄回的原因是
just demonstrating a point right is that
只是表明一点正确是
you can override or change the behavior
您可以覆盖或更改行为
of the responses there so again a
那里的答复，所以再次
gateway is a great place to address
网关是一个解决的好地方
cross-cutting concerns concerns like
横切关注点
authentication authorization zip zipping
身份验证授权zip压缩
and compressions routing you know
和压缩路由知道
anything you want to do in a cross
你想在十字架上做什么
service way in a single place you can do
您可以在一个地方进行服务的方式
that here load balancing all that kind
这里的负载均衡
of stuff lives here at the edge this
的东西住在这里的边缘
should be your first port of call for
应该是您第一个致电的港口
requests coming in from the outside from
来自外部的请求
you know your actual clients talking to
你知道你真正的客户在跟谁说话
your downstream services so you can do
您的下游服务，以便您可以
all sorts of cross-cutting kind of thing
各种交叉的东西
here now
现在这里
in this case I used a custom filter but
在这种情况下，我使用了自定义过滤器
let's look at a custom filter let's look
让我们看一个自定义过滤器
at you know just using a regular filter
你知道只是使用常规过滤器
right so we'll use a well customize the
对，所以我们将使用精心定制的
filtering but we're not going to provide
过滤，但我们不会提供
our own filter this time we're going to
这次我们自己的过滤器
say route is equal to let's see what did
说路线等于让我们看看做了什么
i do there filter oh right
我在那边过滤哦
that belongs to this one here we are and
属于这个，我们是
here we'll say CF 2 dot predicate path
这里我们说CF 2点predicate路径
CF 2 and the URI of course as before we
CF 2和URI当然和我们之前一样
the load-balanced customer service
负载均衡的客户服务
endpoint because why not
端点，因为为什么不
and what we're gonna do here is we're
我们要在这里做的是
gonna take advantage of some of the
会利用一些
pre-built you know out-of-the-box
开箱即用的，您知道的
functionality here so maybe I'll change
功能在这里，所以也许我会改变
this path actually maybe I want the path
这条路其实我可能想要这条路
to be CF 2 asterisk asterisk and we're
是CF 2星号星号，我们是
gonna say that the request is going to
会说请求将
go to customer service just by itself
独自去客户服务
and the filter is going to be the
而过滤器将是
rewrite path so gateway filters dot
重写路径，以便网关过滤点
rewrite path and what we're going to do
重写路径以及我们要做的事情
is were gonna use a regular expression
是要使用正则表达式
to modify the request that's coming in
修改即将到来的请求
to modify the path of the request that's
修改请求的路径
coming in to the edge and then that path
来到边缘然后那条路
will be what's sent to the to the
将被发送到
downstream service right so we could
下游服务正确，所以我们可以
provide a path here but that would be
在这里提供一条路径，但这将是
ignored right it's gonna be replaced
忽略对了，它将被替换
with whatever we substitute it with here
用我们用这里替代的任何东西
so we're gonna say when a request comes
所以我们要说一个请求何时到来
in we're gonna say we want to capture
在我们要说我们想捕捉
this customer ID you know and that could
您知道的该客户ID，并且可以
be anything
什么都可以
and there's our our regular expression
这是我们的正则表达式
never error okay
永远不会出错
and that will provide a replacement so I
这将提供替代品，所以我
want to say instead the path should be
想说相反，路径应该是
whatever we captured as a customer ID
我们捕获为客户ID的任何内容
and they're you know the previous
他们是你知道的
segment of the path here will be
这条路径的路段将是
substituted and extracted and made
替代提取并制成
available here so this is if you've ever
在这里可用，如果您曾经有过
done nginx or if you've ever done mod
做过nginx或者你曾经做过mod
rewrite or anything like that and append
重写或类似的东西并追加
Apache
阿帕奇
this should look very familiar right in
这应该看起来很熟悉
the fact is you can have the same power
事实是你可以拥有相同的力量
here out-of-the-box in your spring cut
在您的 Spring 剪裁中开箱即用
gateway so let's example so what's gonna
网关，让我们以示例为例
happen here when you make a request to
当您请求
localhost 8080 1cf to the edge service
本地8080 1cf到边缘服务
for slash asterisk passing in a customer
用于在客户中传递斜线星号
ID that's what I'm that's what CID is
我就是那个ID那就是那个CID
short for and being being cute for no
简短而可爱，没有
reason it's a customer ID when you when
原因是当您使用客户ID
you provide that
您提供
we're gonna provide a grouped you know
我们将提供您知道的分组
group a pattern loop here and we're
在这里分组模式循环，我们
going to give it a capturing name and
要给它起个名字，
we'll then use that captured element and
然后，我们将使用该捕获的元素并
bind it to the replacement right so
将其绑定到替换权，以便
we're gonna forward the request to
我们将请求转发给
load-balanced customer service for such
负载均衡的客户服务
customers for slash captured cid alright
斜杠的客户捕获的cid好吧
let's see what that looks like so what
让我们看看看起来像什么
do we get that's the first one here I'm
我们得到的是我的第一个吗
just grabbing the ID of something
只是拿东西的ID
alright CF to paste there we are we can
好的CF贴到那里，我们可以
see we got the the one record right we
看到我们得到了一个记录，我们
were able to make a call to localhost CF
能够拨打 localhost CF
to ID and we got the response from the
到ID，我们得到了
downstream service so that worked that
下游服务，从而使
we were able to change things so you
我们能够改变事情，所以你
could change these filters together you
可以一起改变这些过滤器
can do all sorts of things right you can
可以做各种各样的事情
do very custom very dynamic processing
做非常定制的非常动态的处理
here you can even store all those custom
在这里，您甚至可以存储所有这些自定义
filters in the exact order that you want
按照您想要的确切顺序过滤
them in a list as we saw earlier and
如我们先前所见，它们在列表中
then just apply them to different
然后将它们应用于其他
gateway edge edge services or endpoints
网关边缘边缘服务或端点
all right so that's some depsite I think
好吧，那我觉得有些失望
a lot that is what you'd expect and so
这就是您期望的很多，所以
custom more slightly more involved
习俗多一点参与
slightly more interesting options here
这里稍微有趣的选项
one option is to to use a circuit
一种选择是使用电路
breaker right so we've got his dicks on
断路器正确，所以我们把他的家伙
the command line I'm sorry on the class
命令行上课我很抱歉
path and we can use that circuit breaker
路径，我们可以使用该断路器
to protect requests that we make it
保护我们提出的要求
through the edge service to our
通过边缘服务给我们
downstream service and anything that we
下游服务以及我们所做的任何事情
can testify for hystrix
可以作证
for a particular hystrix command can
对于特定的hystrix命令可以
apply here so let's create a route CV
在这里申请，让我们创建一个路线简历
and the predicate will be of course just
predicate当然就是
path CV and the URL will be load
路径CV和URL将被加载
balanced customer - service forward
平衡的客户-服务向前
slash customers and the filter is going
大幅度削减客户，过滤器即将开始
to be gateway filters gateway filters
成为网关过滤器网关过滤器
dot hystrix and let me give it a command
点hystrix，让我给它一个命令
name let's just give it imagine and they
名称，让我们想象一下，他们
do imaginatively enough CB all right
做足够有想象力的认证机构
so that's gonna create a history command
这样就可以创建一个历史命令
it's gonna wrap the invocation of the
它会包装对
downstream service in that command
该命令中的下游服务
now what does that get you out of the
现在是什么让您脱颖而出
box well not much I mean it'll it'll
盒子不多，我是说会
it'll wrap your command in a rapture
它会将您的命令包装成被子
invocation in that command which you can
您可以在该命令中调用
then you know what hold then we turn in
然后你知道什么成立，然后我们上交
HTV 200 for example it'll give you a
以HTV 200为例，它将为您提供
default response if something should go
如果有问题，则默认响应
wrong in the call but you can also
通话中有误，但您也可以
specify things like timeout you can
指定超时等内容
specify how long to wait before you're
指定等待多长时间
given give a request a shot or you know
给一个请求镜头或你知道
etc so you have a lot of control here
等等，所以您这里有很多控制权
you can do per instance name you can
您可以按实例名称进行操作
actually specify per circuit per command
实际上每个命令指定每个电路
you know CV specific configuration or
您知道CV特定的配置或
you can specify default circuit breaker
您可以指定默认断路器
properties so let's do default circuit
属性，让我们做默认电路
breaker properties here I'm gonna go
我要去的断路器属性
ahead and specify hystrix doc command
并指定hystrix doc命令
dot default dot execution that isolation
点默认点执行即隔离
that thread that time out in
那个超时的线程
milliseconds equals 5,000 now we see
毫秒等于5,000现在我们看到
history command default execution in
历史命令默认执行于
isolation thread time' in milliseconds
隔离线程时间（以毫秒为单位）
it goes 5000 i think you can actually
到了5000我想你可以
say cv as well i forget the specific
说简历，我忘了具体
syntax but we're just gonna do default
语法，但我们只是默认
that'll be the global setting here it'll
这将是全球设置
apply to everything once we've done that
一旦完成，就适用于所有内容
instead of calling customer so let's
而不是打电话给客户，所以让我们
call the delay in point remember our
叫点延迟记住我们的
delay in point our delay in point is
延迟点延迟点是
going to respond only after 10 seconds
只会在10秒后回应
so what we're saying here is that we
所以我们在这里说的是
want to timeout and return the default
要超时并返回默认值
response if it takes longer than five
如果需要的时间超过五
seconds obviously these are obscenely
秒显然这些都是淫秽的
large numbers and you're not gonna have
大量的你不会
hopefully you're not gonna have requests
希望你不会有要求
that take anything even close to 5
甚至需要接近5的东西
seconds but I do this because I wanted
秒，但我这样做是因为我想要
us to demonstrate what's happening here
我们来证明这里发生了什么
right so let's let's see what that looks
好的，让我们看一下看起来
like in action ok we start
像在行动，好吧，我们开始
all right
好吧
so let's make a request to circuit
所以让我们请求电路
breaker the endpoint we're gonna get a
打破终点，我们将得到一个
response there you go so we got a 504
响应，你去，所以我们得到了504
gateway timeout that's because the
网关超时是因为
request took too long right so this of
请求花了太长时间，所以这个
course is um you know we're
当然，嗯，你知道我们
demonstrating what would happen if the
演示如果
service was down for example or if it
服务已关闭，例如
was slow to respond obviously the
响应缓慢很明显
service is available right now but it
该服务现在可用，但是它
took too long so we we time-boxed
花了太长时间，所以我们时间装箱了
that request and we got that default
该请求，我们得到了默认值
behavior so you can do all sorts of
行为，以便您可以进行各种
interesting things here you could then
有趣的事情在这里你可以
do what you see here you can actually
做你在这里看到的，你实际上可以
you know then dot whatever and then
你知道然后点什么然后
start processing the response sending
开始处理响应发送
different headers or sending different
不同的标题或发送不同的标题
responses whatever right so a lot of
回应任何正确的事情，所以很多
options here um another thing you can do
这里的选项，您可以做的另一件事
to make your services more robust is to
使您的服务更强大
use rate limiting right so let's look at
使用限速权，让我们看一下
that rate limiting or a delimiter and
速率限制或定界符，以及
what we're going to do here is we're
我们要在这里做的是
going to create a route called RL it's
要创建一个称为RL的路线
gonna have a predicate path RL and the
将有一个predicate路径RL和
URL will be load balanced you know
您知道网址将达到负载均衡
customer - service forward slash
客户服务正斜线
customers and we need to provide a
客户，我们需要提供
filter now this isn't quite the same as
现在过滤器与
the other ones we have to actually
其他我们必须实际
configure a request right limiter so
配置请求权限限制器，以便
let's do that here we're gonna have a
让我们在这里做，我们将有一个
request rate limiter here all right RL
请求速率限制器在这里可以RL
and it's going to need configuration in
并且需要在其中进行配置
order for it to do its work so we're
为了它做它的工作，所以我们
going to say our l dot ply and we're
要说我们的l点层，我们
going to give it some tube full of
要给它装满一些
parameters which we can use you know
我们可以使用的参数你知道
what you need to know is that that
您需要知道的是
request that request rate limiter
请求该请求速率限制器
factory meaning thing is going to that
工厂的意思是要去那
request rate limit or gateway filter
请求速率限制或网关过滤器
factory is going to in turn depend upon
工厂将反过来取决于
a particular implementation of a right
权利的特定实现
limiter well I happen to know that that
限制器好吧，我碰巧知道
implementation is the Redis rate limit
实施是Redis速率限制
limiter and that's why I have
限制器，这就是为什么我有
Redis on the classpath we're also going
Redis也在类路径上
to need spring security so I'm gonna go
需要Spring Security ，所以我要去
ahead and restore that we'll talk about
继续并恢复我们将要谈论的内容
why in a second but we have Redis and we
为什么一秒钟，但我们有Redis，我们
have the security so we know that's
有安全感，所以我们知道
gonna use a Redis based rate limiter the
将使用基于Redis的速率限制器
reason it's using a reddest Redis based
使用基于Reddest的Redis的原因
rate limiter is because it's going to
速率限制器是因为它将
it's going to keep safe right it's gonna
它会保持安全的权利
have to keep State it's gonna keep count
必须保持状态它将保持计数
if you will of requests made into the
如果您愿意将请求
downstream service it needs to know how
下游服务，它需要知道如何
to differentiate requests I suppose you
区分我想你的要求
could make it make a rate learning
可以使它成为学习率
policy that said that all requests to
说明所有要求的政策
this service should be capped at you
该服务应限制在您身上
know and requests for a second whatever
知道并要求一秒钟
but this default implementation is going
但是这个默认实现
to expect a particular key and so that
期待一个特定的钥匙，这样
key you can provide it any way you want
密钥，您可以根据需要提供任何方式
the key that it's using by default and
默认情况下使用的密钥
in the default right a straight limiter
在默认情况下是一个直的限制器
configuration here is what is it it's
这里的配置是什么
the principal it's the security
原则就是安全
principal so that's what we're gonna do
校长，这就是我们要做的
is we're going to use the security
是我们要使用安全性
principle to give it a key based on the
原则，根据
name of the user making the requests so
发出请求的用户名，因此
we need to configure spring security for
我们需要为
that to work what this configuration
该工作什么这种配置
says is we're expecting to get five
说我们期望得到五个
requests per second with a burst
每秒请求数
capacity of ten so that's a very low low
容量为十，所以非常低
level obviously you know some websites
级别显然您知道一些网站
do ten million requests per second so
每秒执行一千万个请求
this is just for a demo right all right
这只是一个演示，好吧
so let's do that we're gonna have to
所以我们要做的是
configure spring security first and
首先配置spring安全性，然后
reactive spring security no less so
反应性Spring 安全性同样如此
we'll say enable web flex security
我们会说启用Web Flex安全性
there's that and we need to address two
就是这样，我们需要解决两个问题
concerns authentication authorization
有关身份验证授权
right good
对的好
I'm gonna say beam reactive sorry map
我要说束反应对不起地图
reactive user detail service
反应式用户详细信息服务
authentication and when I say new map
身份验证以及我说的新地图
users dot with default password encoder
用户使用默认密码编码器点
okay and build roles with a user and the
好的，并与用户和
user name will be user because why not
用户名将是用户，因为为什么不
password vpw so there's a very simple
密码vpw，所以非常简单
you know authentication mechanism we're
你知道认证机制
going to use a user detail service a
将使用用户详细信息服务
reactive user detail service that has
具有以下功能的反应式用户详细信息服务
one user with a default password and
一个具有默认密码的用户，以及
Kozar encoder with the username user and
使用用户名user和的Kozar编码器
the password password and the role is to
密码，密码的作用是
equal to user and we need now a
等于用户，我们现在需要
authorization element okay Dean and here
授权元素好，Dean和这里
this is going to expect void can you
这将期待虚无你能
know authorization learn to inject the
知道授权学习注入
server HTTP security let's see
服务器HTTP安全性让我们看看
security and when I say return security
安全和我说退货安全
dot it'll just just see what that gives
点它只会看到什么
us
我们
filter chain there we are that's the
过滤器链那里就是
return value okay now security dot
返回值好了现在安全点
authorize exchange path matches is going
授权交换路径匹配正在进行
to be equal to a rate limiter all right
等于一个限速器
so anything going to rate limit is going
所以任何要进行速率限制的事情都会发生
to be it's going to require
这将是需要的
authentication but otherwise you know in
身份验证，但您知道
the exchange will be permit all so
这样的交换将被允许
everything else will be wide open just
其他一切都将敞开
that one endpoint the right limit in
一个端点的正确限制
point or require authentication will say
点或要求身份验证会说
end they should be basic and very good
最后他们应该是基础的，非常好
so there's our there's our configuration
所以这里有我们的配置
and that's just very basic reactors
那只是非常基本的反应堆
between security we actually looked at
我们实际研究的安全性之间
reactive spring security in our previous
我们之前的反应式Spring 安全性
installments so you should refer to that
分期付款，所以您应该参考
video for more details with that said I
视频的更多细节，说我
think we have everything in place so
认为我们一切就绪
let's go ahead and restart the
让我们继续并重新启动
application and let's confirm that the
应用程序，然后确认
basics work first
基础工作首先
all right that's all we're trying to do
好吧，这就是我们想要做的
right now is just to confirm that given
现在只是为了确认给定
an authenticated attempt or request you
经过验证的尝试或要求您
use
采用
pwe HTTP local host 8080 won and we said
pwe HTTP localhost 8080赢得了，我们说
our ell I said that works right we got
我说我的工作正常，我们得到了
no problem we had no problem making
没问题，我们没问题
those requests now I can't make five
这些要求我现在不能提出五个
requests a second with my hand here
在这里请求我的手
actually so I I'm gonna you know for the
其实所以我我要你知道
purpose of demonstration here I'm gonna
我在这里示范的目的
do something a little little ugly but
做点丑事
it'll it'll work we're going to create a
它将起作用，我们将创建一个
client in the same Java process this
同一Java客户端处理
should obviously just you know if this
显然应该知道你是否
was a test it would live somewhere else
是一个测试，它可以住在其他地方
but I just want to have something
但我只想吃点东西
hammering the service so that we can see
锤击服务，以便我们看到
the responses that come back so we're
回来的回应，所以我们
going to create a very simple
要创建一个非常简单的
application runner and in order to do it
应用程序运行器并为此做
we're going to need a reactive web
我们将需要一个被动的网站
client so web client dot that create dot
客户端，因此Web客户端点创建点
or sorry builder dot filter exchange
或对不起构建器点过滤器交换
filter functions basic authentication
过滤器功能基本认证
user and PW and build that C so it's our
用户和PW并构建该C，所以这是我们的
web client and when we make those
网络客户端，当我们制作那些
requests we're going to we're going to
我们要去的要求
generate a number of requests so our
产生许多要求，所以我们
goal is to generate more than five
目标是产生五个以上
requests per second obviously so we'll
每秒明显的请求，因此我们将
say flux dot from stream and I think we
说流中的磁通点，我想我们
can use something in the JDK stream
可以在JDK流中使用某些东西
library to generate a sequence of values
库以生成值序列
into stream dot range is 0 to 100 and
流点范围是0到100
we're going to flat map that response or
我们将平铺该响应或
that data so the integer or we want it
该数据，所以整数或我们想要它
to be boxed that's what it's complaining
被装箱就是它的抱怨
about a stream of integer is done it's
关于整数流完成了
not it's not a stream of integer it's a
不是整数流，而是
in stream by default so we have to unbox
默认情况下在流中，因此我们必须取消装箱
it and they're going to say for each
它，他们将为每个发言
number which actually you know we don't
您实际上知道我们不知道的号码
care about in other languages we could
关心其他语言，我们可以
just say that but we say number or
只是说，但我们说数字或
whatever who cares
不管谁在乎
so for each number we want to
所以对于每个数字我们想要
make a request so client get that URI
发出请求，以便客户端获取该URI
equals HTTP we're gonna call ourself
等于HTTP，我们将自称
basically on our own port calling the
基本上在我们自己的港口上
right now edit endpoint and I'm going to
现在编辑端点，我要
get an exchange response and we're gonna
得到交换回应，我们将
map that client response into something
将客户的反应映射为某种东西
that we can use so CR not to entity
我们可以使用的CR而不是实体
we're gonna we don't care about the
我们将不在乎
payload we just want the string back in
有效负载，我们只想让字符串返回
a problem and then we want to map that
一个问题，然后我们想将其映射
so we're gonna map a response to to a
所以我们将响应映射到
message right into a string data format
将消息直接转换为字符串数据格式
you you know the status will be this and
你知道状态就是这个
the body will be this and we'll say our
身体将是这个，我们会说我们的
e dot status code value and our
点状态代码值和我们的
get body alright so there's our message
身体好，所以我们有信息
that we've mapped and now we just absque
我们已经绘制的地图，现在我们只是古怪的
ribe system.out.print mine alright that
ribe system.out.print我的好吧
looks ok that looks like it's that'll
看起来不错，看起来像那样
give us what we want let's try its run
给我们我们想要的，让我们尝试一下
this application and we should see that
这个应用程序，我们应该看到
while while five of them get through for
而当其中五个通过
every second not all of them do right
并非每一秒钟他们都做得对
there you go
你去
so there you see one got through most of
所以你看到一个通过了大部分
them didn't because we're going a little
他们不是因为我们要走一点
too fast there he goes five got through
太快了，他走了五个
at a time and then most of time etc by
一次，然后大部分时间等
the way this is not necessarily
这种方式不一定
sequential right I'm using a new active
顺序权我正在使用新的主动
support here so by definition every
在这里支持，所以根据定义
single one of these requests could have
这些请求中有一个可能有
happened in concurrence or or not so the
是否同时发生
status code for 29 is too many requests
状态代码为29的请求太多
right so it's rejected it's right
对，所以它被拒绝是对的
limited to requests to the downstream
限于对下游的请求
service per user if we had if we were
每个用户的服务（如果有）
authenticated with a different user then
然后由其他用户验证
this wouldn't be this wouldn't be a
这不会是这不会是一个
problem alright so we've looked at just
问题很好，所以我们只看了
a few things you can do with spring
Spring 可以做的几件事
cloud gateway the application is kind of
云网关的应用程序是
you know
你懂
it's really simple you can I'm sure you
这很简单，我可以确定
can imagine a lot of things you can do
可以想像很多事情你可以做
beyond this one thing that's worth
超越这一件事值得
understanding is that there of course if
理解当然是如果
there's integration with the rest of the
与其余的整合
stack you know in spring cloud so you
把你知道的叠放在 Spring 的云里，所以你
can see spring like the gateway is being
可以像网关一样看到 Spring
used in other places that the ability to
在其他地方使用的能力
manipulate the routes is very useful
操纵路线非常有用
there's also surfaced information about
还有关于
these raps you can see here there are
这些说唱，你可以在这里看到
actuator in point so if I were to go to
执行器就好了，所以如果我要去
this end point here let's see curl HTTP
这个端点在这里让我们看看curl HTTP
localhost:8080 one we are all right so
localhost ：8080我们没事吧
the actuator end points you know I can
执行器终点，你知道我可以
me plate these routes I can interrogate
我把这些路线我可以询问
them I can manipulate them I can do all
他们我可以操纵他们，我可以做的一切
sorts of things to dynamically add or
可以动态添加的各种内容或
modify routes in the running process so
在运行过程中修改路由，以便
these actuator points surface that
这些执行器指向表面
information that's very convenient and
信息非常方便
you know we have just the beginnings as
你知道我们只是个开始
I say just the beginnings of our of the
我说的只是我们的开始
possibility right we've done a number of
可能性，我们已经做了很多
things here fairly straightforwardly
这里的事情很简单
I've demonstrated a number of concepts
我已经展示了许多概念
here but there's so much more and I and
在这里，但还有更多，我和
I'm sure you can imagine them as well so
我相信你也可以想象他们
with that thank you so much for watching
非常感谢您的收看
and we'll see you next time
下次再见
you
您